Katie A. Shelton

kashelton17@gmail.com Chicago, IL 60091

OBJECTIVE

Enthusiastic, flexible candidate with 5 years of work experience in recording, interpreting and analyzing data in a fast-paced environment, knowledge of python, javascript, html and several others programs. A quick learner and great attention to detail.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Global Manager and Data Analyst/Chemist - FreshAir Sensor, Lebanon NH, January 2017 - Present

- Managing junior lab employees
- Managing data analysis team in Pakistan
- Worked independently to develop H2S sensors and worked with clients to test and incorporate the sensors
- Day to day: Write performance reports and QA for Pakistan team, manage in house lab projects as well as helping develop programs to automate production for FreshAir devices.
- Interpret data using statistical techniques and provide reports with data visualizations to present data information on product to managing team
- Develop and improve data collection and procedures using skills in python
- Clear communication skills aimed at understanding demanding project requirements and providing corresponding services
- Trained interns in chemistry department on procedures and techniques

Website Design Experience Summer/Fall 2016

- Designed and implemented a website for the <u>Holy Rosary School childcare program</u> in Kewaunee, WI (p2518966.wixsite.com/childcare)
- Designed and implemented a website for the <u>Kewaunee Fitness Center</u> in Kewaunee, WI (kewauneefitness.org)

Research Assistant - Analytical Chemistry, Bucknell University, Spring 2016

- Worked collaboratively with Department Chair to create a teaching lab for a lower level chemistry course analyzing ingredients in different types of sodas using HPLC
- Responsible for creating, analyzing and distributing organized data to students and faculty

Research Assistant - Environmental Chemistry, Bucknell University, May-July 2014

- Researched interactions of nanoparticles with various forms of clay; Presented a poster at end of internship
- Experience in various chemistry labs and using state of the art instruments such as XRD and mass spectrometer.

Sales Associate, Target June 2015 to December 2016, Green Bay, WI and Glenview, IL

- Managed inventory and attended to the needs of customers to ensure satisfaction
- Trainer to junior employees

EDUCATION

Bucknell University, Lewisburg, PA, Bachelor of Science in Chemistry, May 2016

Relevant classes: Computer Science (Python), Analytical and Physical Chemistry, Calculus 1, 2 and 3

Bucknell University, Lewisburg, PA, Bachelor of Arts in German, May 2016

Study Program Abroad: Berlin, Germany: All classes taught in German

Relevant Online Coursework

Northwestern Web Development Bootcamp – March 2021-September 2021 <u>Portfolio</u> (https://kashelton17.github.io/14-hw-portfolio3/) Completed Google IT Support Professional Certificate through Coursera November 2020

Completed Python for Data Science and AI by IBM through Coursera May 2020s

ACTIVITIES

Upper Valley Rugby Club, Spring 2018 – Present

Chicago Marathon, (October 2019, October 2021) Raised over \$3000 for National MS Society

Bucknell Symphony Orchestra, (Fall 2012 – Spring 2016) Semi-professional violin player: 1st Violin Chi Omega

Sorority, Bucknell University, Member since October 2013

COMPETENCIES

Technical skills: Python, Javascript, Node.js, HTML, CSS, SQL programming languages, Microsoft Office (Access, Excel, Word, PowerPoint), Arduino, Soldering Laboratory skills: UV-Vis, centrifuge, HPLC, XRD

Other competencies: Excellent time management, organizational skills, attention to detail and strong writing skills